Vanessa Kasun

Omaha, Nebraska, United States



vkasun@aiminstitute.org



402-699-8781



linkedin.com/in/vanessa-kasun-15393a139

Summary

Creative Web Developer and Code Instructor at AIM Code School, with a Degree in Computer Science. Learned how to use JavaScript to build responsive websites, mobile app, and interactive features that drive growth and improve UI & UX. Specializing in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Vue, Java, SQL, ReactJS and jQuery

Experience



Full-Stack JavaScript Curriculum Developer

AIM Institute

Apr 2021 - Present (5 months +)

This JavaScript Course covers the intricacies of JavaScript and the technologies that power a modern full-stack development workflow. This includes client and server side scripting, single web-page applications utilizing the MVN structure, Node package management, and JSON data storage. Students will finish the class having built a fully functional client-server application.

High-Level Overview of Topic Covered:

Programming Structure Object Oriented Programming Regular Expressions/ Asynchronous Programming Client Side Programming Server Side Programming **Debugging Node JS Applications** Database/RESTful Services

Template Engines



Java Instructor

AIM Institute

Oct 2020 - Present (11 months +)

Instruct Java FullStack Course, covering a wide range of material. The final outcome is a fully built webbased Vue application.

Java Course Content Covered includes:

Basic OOP Concepts

Java Intro

Advanced Java Concepts

NoSQL

MySQL

SQL

HTML/CSS/Javascript

JPS/Servlets

Spring

RESTful Web Services

Cloud(Server Management, Heroku, CI/CD Pipelines

Vue



Foundations Web Development Instructor

AIM Institute

Jan 2020 - Present (1 year 8 months +)

Teach students that have no previous technical background about the fundamentals of web development and create a website using code. The course covers...

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

jQuery

UI/UX

Git



Course Creator for Front-End Web Development Course

AIM Institute

Jan 2020 - Present (1 year 8 months +)

Create Course Curriculum for Front-End Foundations of Web Development Course including Pre and Post Course Assessments as well as course quizzes to gage understanding. Students must create two in-class websites and one final project of their choice using the skills and knowledge obtained throughout the course. Topics Created and Covered:

IJX

UI

Design

IDE's

Git

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

jQuery

Bootstrap

React

Interpersonal Skills

Developer Eticasy

Developer Success in the workforce

Developer Resume Building



Heartland Developer Conference 2020 Speaker(ReactJS)

AIM Institute

Sep 2020 - Sep 2020 (1 month)

Create a breakout session tutorial about coding a ReactJS app from scratch. At the end of the session participants have a complete simple-todo-list app ready to deploy to the web. Session Topics Covered: Components

States

Props Prop Drilling CSS integration UUID JavaScript ES6 ect.

Frontend Web Developer

Paul Anderson for Congress

Mar 2020 - Mar 2020 (1 month)

Created a website for running republican 2020 candidate, Paul Anderson.

Foundations Web Development Instructron

Omaha South Magnet High School

Jan 2020 - Jan 2020 (1 month)

Teach students that have no previous technical background about the fundamentals of web development and create a website using code. The course covers...

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

jQuery

SaaS

UI/UX

Git

Github

Deployments

Frontend Web Developer

North 24th Street BID

Sep 2019 - Nov 2019 (3 months)

I created a website for the Board Members of the North 24th Street Business Improvement District. With the website being presented to the city of Omaha, I was instructed to make a very informative site that would be suitable for members of our local Government to look at and get a good grasp on the concepts and ideas of the North 24th Street improvement project.

Education

Metropolitan Community College

Associate's degree, Computer Science

2017 - 2019

Information Technology Front End Web Development

R Papillion-Lavista High School

General Diploma, General Studies 2009 - 2012

Skills

Microsoft Office • Microsoft Excel • Customer Service • Social Media • Web Development • Web Design • Technical Support • Front-end Development • Computer Science • Microsoft Word

Honors & Awards



A HDC Top Speaker - AIM Institute

Oct 2020

Create and presented a demonstration of how to create a simple React web application. I placed third as the top best speaker session.